Sivakumar Vunnam

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER

	sivakumarvunnam1@gmail.com		+1-603-943-9	9002	Lewisville, Texas
in	https://www.linkedin.com/in/sivakumary	/unr	nam/ 🌐 htt _l	ps://sival	kumarvunnam.github.id

SUMMARY

A Successful DevOps Engineer with Over 5 years of professional Experience dedicated to DevOps Automation, AWS (cost optimization, governance) and tools consolidation. supporting on-premises and cloud infrastructure (AWS, Azure) with a strong background on DevOps tools to deploy web applications, API's, User Interface Applications and Databases.

SKILLS

Jenkins	• • • • •	Packer	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$
AWS	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$	SonarQube	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$
Docker	••••	Jfrog	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$
Kubernetes	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$	Python	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$
Shell Scripting	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$	Yaml/Json	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$
Vagrant	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$	SaltStack	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$
Microsoft Azure	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ	Ansible	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$
Databases	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ	EFK	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$
Google Cloud (GCP)	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$	Prometheus	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$
Testing	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ	Grafana	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

EXPERIENCE

STAFF DEVOPS ENGINEER

Blackhawk Network Inc - Lewisville, Texas Sep 2018 - Present

- AWS Standardization: Standardizing CloudFormation templates across all environments for Hawk Marketplace Core Production migration to Oregon using Service Catalog. Core Production DR capability in Virginia for target platforms using Service Catalog.
- Cost Management: AWS account deprecation and decommission. Spot instances coverage >80% in all BHN Core Non-Prod accounts, Hawk Marketplace Non-Prod accounts. Reserved Instances coverage > 80% in all core Prod accounts with a stable baseline.
- CI/CD: Jenkins Enterprise pipeline adoption for across BHN Organization using Jenkins Shared Libraries
- AWS Governance: AWS golden image creation using packer and saltstack (Linux and Windows) and adoption of AWS Linux
- Hawk Redeem implementation in AWS: Migrating application from Datacenter to AWS. worked with aws cloud partners mactores team.
- Development tool consolidation: Synergy/Marketplace OpenSource Jenkins and bitbucket migration to Core BHN Cloudbees Enterprise Jenkins
- Extensively worked on AWS Migration for the project Hawk Incentives from IBM Data Center to AWS Oregon Region
- Automated CI/CD for Markteplace Applications using BitBucket, Jenkins, Jrog, SonarQube, S3, AWS CodeDeploy

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER

Saibersys Inc | Nexient Inc, Ann Arbor, MI Oct 2017 - Aug 2018

- AWS Migration for the project Hawk Incentives from IBM Data Center to AWS Oregon Region
- Handling day to day tickets opened in the rally ticketing system.
- Writing cloud formation templates for AWS migration to Automate the AWS Services VPC, Bastion hosts, PAN Data Server, Hawk Incentives Applications and Web servers with aws high availability and fault tolerance architecture
- Worked on infrastructure/apm monitoring solution new relic
- Worked on setting up logging Splunk for production and non-prod environment EFK
- Hand on knowledge in working Amazon web services (IAM, EC2, EBS, S3, Cloud Front, Autoscaling and Load Balancing, VPC, RDS, ROUTE 53)
- Setup and maintain the CI/CD using Jenkins for AWS Code Deploy and AWS Cloud Formation
- Extensively worked on writing the Code Builds for AMP-Studio React (UI). Configured it Nginx as a reverse proxy
- Working on implementing the Microservice called email microservice which connect the spring boot backend and send email templates to the customers.
- Did the POC with the (Terraform, EKS Cluster, Application Load Balancer, API gateway, Lambda, Aurora MySQL)
- Created CI/CD for Email Microservice

DevOps Engineer

Saibersys Inc | HGST a Western Digital, San Jose, CA Jul 2016 - Aug 2017

- Installation and configuring the EXSI server on Dell and Super Micro bare metal provisioning hardware's
- Configured Launched EXSI Server's as a Cluster using the VSphere and VCenter.
- Installation, configuring and administration the Linux VM's on ESXI servers Using Vagrant
- Implemented the automated factory installation on ActiveScale X100 and ActiveScale P100 hardware,
- Supporting TAAS (Test Drive as a Service) multiple geographical locations from Belgium, Las Vegas and San Jose.
- Working on container orchestration tools Kubernetes for Customizability, Scalability, and High availability of Jenkins
- Experience in writing the YAML files for Jenkins Job Builder for Dynamic Jenkins jobs configuration.
- Installation, configuration and administration experience in revision management tool Gitlab, Jenkins, Maven, Nexus, Docker, Docker Swarm
- Written Dockerfiles for to Isolate Java Spring Boot, Python, Nodejs, Angular Applications code in to docker images.
- To Build and Deploy the code created custom docker slave images with environment depencies
- Written scripts for Jenkins home backup daily into JFrog Artifactory
- Worked on POC to deploy TAAS on Kubernetes ecosystem and configured EFK to collect TAAS logs and stored it in centralized environment.

DevOps Engineer

Saibersys Inc | Cisco San Jose, CA Dec 2015 - Apr 2016

- Handling day to day tickets opened in JIRA ticketing system
- Setting up Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment process using Git, Jenkins, Maven, Nexus, SonarQube, Tomcat application sever s instances
- Working on Ansible to automate application deployments.
- Written Ansible playbooks to create a custom application environment for Java and DotNet Applications
- Experience In installing and configuring configuration management tool puppet. Experience in writing new Puppet Modules. Puppetizing the configurations across different environments.
- Experience in writing puppet modules for setting up new environments and for administration use.
- Working on puppet to automate Configuration management & Applications.
- Puppet to manage Web Applications, Config Files, Database, Users Mount Points, and Packages.

BUILD AND RELEASE ENGINEER

Unwired Labs, Hyderabad, Telangana Jan 2013 - Jul 2014

- Experience in Installation and configurations for Linux distributions operating system.
- Experience in working Agile Environment.
- Hands-on experience in Installation and Configuring and Administration tasks in Source code management tools like GIT, Subversion. Continuous integration tools like Jenkins, Hudson.
- Maintained protocol like TCP/IP, NIS, NFS, DNS, SNMP, VSFTP and DHCP FTP and Samba on Linux systems.
- Responsible for setting up Cron jobs scripts on production servers.
- Responsible for using build tools like Maven and Ant for the building of deploying the artifacts such as Jar, war & ear from source code.
- Responsible for storing the artifact's in Nexus repositories. After Building the code in Continuous Integration.
- Responsible for Installing and configuring setup for clustered environment with Apache Tomcat Application Server for automatic Deployment.
- Implemented a Continuous Delivery framework using Jenkins, Maven, Nexus and Chef in Linux environment.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Rivier University - Nashua, NH Aug 2014 - Dec 2015

• GPA - 3.8/4.0

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, COMPUTER SCIENCE

Acharya Nagarjuna University - Guntur, AP Aug 2009 - May 2013

• CGPA - 3.3/4.0

CERTIFICATION

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associat (saa-c01)

Amazon Web Services - 2018

PERSONAL SKILLS

Problem solving
Team Leader
Planning strategically

From Leader

Planning strategically

Team Leader

Planning strategically

Planning strategically

From Leader

Attention to detail

REFERAL

Available on request.